Samuel Tracy

Phone: (916) 764-9002 Email: stracy@g.harvard.edu Web: https://seasamgo.github.io

Ph.D. candidate in Biostatistics at Harvard University focusing on methods for failure time data and single-cell sequencing data. In particular: developing and adapting sampling techniques, optimization theory, adjustments for missingness, clustering methods, and dimensionality reduction. My advisor is Dr. Guo-Cheng Yuan. I am also an advocate for open-source development, reproducible research and diversity in STEM.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Biostatistics	Harvard University	2019^{1}
M.A. Biostatistics	Harvard University	2016
B.S. Applied Mathematics, magna cum laude	UC San Diego	2014

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Consultant 09/2017 – present

Harvard University, Boston, MA

Department of Biostatistics Consulting Center

Student Intern 03/2013 – 06/2013

Clinical and Translational Research Institute, San Diego, CA

Clinical data visualization and analysis under Dr. Ronghui Xu and James Proudfoot

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant 01/2016 – present

T.H. Chan Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA

BST 210 Applied Regression Analysis (Spring 2016, 2017)

BST 226 Applied Longitudinal Analysis (Spring 2018)

Instructor and Administrator 01/2015 - 08/2017

StatStart, Boston, MA

Student-run high school program in statistical computing for minorities in STEM (Summer 2015, 2016, 2017)

Teaching Assistant 09/2013 - 06/2014

UC San Diego, San Diego, CA

MATH 10ABC Calculus Series (Fall 2013, Winter 2014, Spring 2014)

Academic Liaison 01/2013 – 03/2013

Fallbrook High School, Fallbrook, CA

All-subjects tutor and liaison through the UC San Diego Educational Studies Department

¹anticipated

PROJECTS

Chen, T., Tracy, S., Uno, H. Minimal-area confidence bands for failure time data.

Tracy, S., Dries, R., Yuan, G.C. scRNA-seq dropout imputation via subsampling of genes.

Tracy, S., Yuan, G.C. Scoring lineage prediction with single-cell data.

PUBLICATIONS

Talbot, O., Ocampo, A., Tracy, S., Mosesso, K., Rahman, A., and Pagano, M. StatStart 2015. *ASA: The Statistics Teacher Network*, 87: 4-8, 2016.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Software – R, MATLAB, Stata, Java, C++, Python

Interests – tumor evolution and heterogeneity, systems architecture, cyber security

SOFTWARE

Co-creator and maintainer of the R package optband (on CRAN and GitHub), a package for statistical confidence bands applied to failure time data and optimized by area.

SELECTED INVOLVEMENT

Graduate Student Council, Department Representative	09/2015 - 08/2017
Roxbury Prep Tutoring, Co-director	09/2016 - 05/2017
Roxbury Prep Tutoring, Coordinator	09/2015 - 05/2016
Student Conduct Code Committee, Student Representative	01/2014 - 06/2014
Global Water Brigades, Honduras Brigade Member	01/2014 - 03/2014

REFERENCES

Yuan, Guo-Cheng

Associate Professor, Department of Biostatistics, Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health Address: 360 Longwood Ave, Room 1060, Boston, MA 02215

Tel: (617) 582-8532 Email: gcyuan@jimmy.harvard.edu

Xu, Ronghui

Professor, Department of Mathematics, University of California, San Diego

Address: 9500 Gilman Drive #0112, La Jolla, CA 92093

Tel: (858) 534-6380 Email: rxu@ucsd.edu

¹anticipated